ICE recently murdered a woman who was part of a community effort to stop migrant raids. ICE feels
like it can do whatever it wants and therefore we need to think about what we can do to stop ICE.
And there's four ways that we can do this. The first thing is to have continued direct action.
That means people out on the street confronting ICE and literally stopping them from doing what
they want to do. Snatching people, putting them in vans, and taking them off to detention centers.
It's this form of direct action that has actually proven to be very effective. We can't wait for the
next election. We can't wait for laws to change. And we cannot rely on the moral conscience of the
oppressor. Only through direct confrontation can anything change for migrants to have a better life.
The second thing we need to also do is not let the Democrats steal the narrative. Democrats pretend to
resist Trump. They pretend to care about migrant rights. But of course, may I remind viewers that
actually during Obama's presidency, there were more deportations on a yearly basis than during Trump.
Biden, for instance, actually continued to expand the border wall. What happened to all those demands
to bring it down, of course, right? And we even heard from Tim Walls, the governor of Minnesota,
that he is going to deploy the National Guard. He's not deploying the National Guard against ICE.
He's going to be doing this against protesters. By the way, which he already did previously,
for instance, against Black Lives Matter protests. So there you have it.
We cannot rely on the Democrats. They're going to try to co-op this, and that cannot happen.
The third thing is the need to build alliances. What we might call a Rainbow Coalition. The Rainbow
Coalition was developed by the Black Panther Party in the 60s and 1970s. The Black Panthers were
obviously resisting white supremacy against Black people. But in order to continue this resistance,
they allied with other groups. For instance, the Indigenous American Indian Movement, Puerto Rican
Nationalists, even white working-class organizations, for instance. And this is what they did,
and actually proved very effective and very scary for those in power. In the case of migrant rights,
let's think about the fact that the tactics that are used against migrants are very similar to the
police tactics and military tactics used by Israel against Palestinians. Let's think about why migrants
are coming to the United States in the first place. Well, a lot of them are coming from Latin America,
which has been destabilized by the United States. And therefore, we also need to ensure that we're
resisting the invasion of Venezuela as well. Bringing these things together and critically thinking
about it and bringing it together so that we can form a coalition. The fourth and final thing is,
and this is going to be my most controversial one, is if you live in a state that has an open carry law,
exercise your right. It's perfectly legal. You have the right to open carry. And this has also proven
an effect of ensuring that state violence remains to a minimum. For instance, the Black Panther Party
used to exercise their right in the 1960s, and they found that police harassment happened a lot less.
So there you have it. Those are four ways to actually resist ICE. Please leave your comments,
keep it constructive, and I hope to, if you can like and share, that'd be great. Thank you.